<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Jack Baty's Notes</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net</link>
<description>Jack takes notes</description>
	<item>
<title>Thinking about cameras</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/Thinkingaboutcameras.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I'm still feeling guilty about buying the M10-R. </p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/Thinkingaboutcameras.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Chris Locke (1947&#x2013;2021)</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/ChrisLocke19472021.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I cut my blogging teeth wanting to be <a href="http://www.rageboy.com">Rageboy</a>. We lost Chris Locke this week. <a href="https://blogs.harvard.edu/doc/2021/12/21/rage-in-peace/">Here's Doc Searls</a>.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/ChrisLocke19472021.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Undecided</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/Undecided.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Well, as long as I'm undecided about what to write where, I may as well do a little bit of it here, no?</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/23/Undecided.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Where is this hosted?</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/08/Whereisthishosted.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Is it funny that I don't even remember where this site is hosted? Maybe not "funny" so much as symptomatic of the entire problem. Update: It's using <a href="https://pages.cloudflare.com">Cloudflare Pages</a>.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/08/Whereisthishosted.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Alex reminded me about this blog</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/08/Alexremindedmeaboutthisb.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Alex reminded me about this blog, so I just had to open Tinderbox and play with it. I don't know if it will go anywhere, since I'm in the middle of another "where do I post stuff!?" crisis. This, though, remains an option.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/12/08/Alexremindedmeaboutthisb.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>I'll come back to this later</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Illcomebacktothislater.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I was all over rebuilding this blog yesterday. This morning I planned to gut the HTML/CSS and try to clean things up a bit myself rather than <strike>stealing</strike> borrowing Dave's legacy markup. It wasn't long before I ran into the road block called "Modern Web Development" and lost my mojo. Maybe it's that I feel like crap from the Moderna booster vaccine yesterday, but I think I'll let this idle for a bit.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Illcomebacktothislater.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>I went to a bookstore yesterday</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Iwenttoabookstoreyesterd.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Have you ever been to a bookstore? I have, and they are wonderful.</p>
<p>I needed to run some errands yesterday and happened to drive by <a href="https://www.schulerbooks.com/">Schuler Books</a>, an independent store based in Michigan and one I've been going to for decades.</p>
<p>It's been a couple of years since I've been inside a bookstore and oh my goodness what a feeling. Am I the only one that feels a certain calming wonder upon entering any bookstore? Maybe not the giant chain stores because they feel a little yucky to me and it takes the fun out of it, but the local(ish) stores that have been in the neighborhood forever. Mmmm.</p>
<p>Shopping for books by walking around amongst the shelves is an immeasurably better experience than endlessly clicking on the computer. The only reviews to be had are a few hand-written notes in front of some books. One per book. No aggregated score. No algorithm. No ads.</p>
<p>I bought the <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/termination-shock-9780063028050/9780063028050">new Neal Stephenson book</a> (which is honestly why I was there in the first place). But I also bought <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-ten-thousand-doors-of-january-9780316421997/9780316421973">The Ten Thousand Doors of January</a> and a <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-selected-poetry-of-rainer-maria-rilke-bilingual-edition/9780679722014">book of poetry by Rilke</a>. During checkout, they said that they loved the Rilke book and how it included the original German-language versions. They then inserted a bookmark in each book, and packed them all into a crisp paper bag and said, "Enjoy!"</p>

<p>Bookstores are the best.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Iwenttoabookstoreyesterd.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>About that M10 Monochrom</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/AboutthatM10Monochrom.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I've been thinking a lot lately about getting a Leica M10 Monochrom. I know, I know, it's a bad idea. I had the Leica Q2 Monochrom and sold it. But but but! The idea is that if I consider myself a primarily black and white photographer, and I do, there's nothing better than the M10M. Except it's way too expensive for something so limited. Then I had a genius idea. What about an M10-P again? But, and here's the genius part, set up Lightroom to convert raw images to black and white on import! That way I never have to actually see each image in color and decide if I should convert it to black and white. It's darn close to shooting B&W right in the camera. Later, if I do happen to get curious, I can peek at the original color version, just in case. Ha? Ya?</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/AboutthatM10Monochrom.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>No news is good news</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Nonewsisgoodnews.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I have been avoiding news sites, mostly successfully, for a while now. Life is better without knowing about things I neither care nor can do anything about. The Economist once a week is enough. When I do accidentally dip into NYT or similar, I am reminded that the Bad Guys really are winning and it depresses me to no end.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Nonewsisgoodnews.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Social features</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Socialfeatures.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Adding social or collaborative features to an app invariably makes that app worse. (Unless of course that's what the app is <i>for</i>)</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Socialfeatures.html</guid>
</item>
</channel>

</rss>