<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Jack Baty's Notes</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net</link>
<description>Jack takes notes</description>
	<item>
<title>Where is this hosted?</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/08/Whereisthishosted.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Is it funny that I don't even remember where this site is hosted? Maybe not "funny" so much as symptomatic of the entire problem.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/08/Whereisthishosted.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Alex reminded me about this blog</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/08/Alexremindedmeaboutthisb.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Alex reminded me about this blog, so I just had to open Tinderbox and play with it. I don't know if it will go anywhere, since I'm in the middle of another "where do I post stuff!?" crisis. This, though, remains an option.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/08/Alexremindedmeaboutthisb.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>I'll come back to this later</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Illcomebacktothislater.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I was all over rebuilding this blog yesterday. This morning I planned to gut the HTML/CSS and try to clean things up a bit myself rather than <strike>stealing</strike> borrowing Dave's legacy markup. It wasn't long before I ran into the road block called "Modern Web Development" and lost my mojo. Maybe it's that I feel like crap from the Moderna booster vaccine yesterday, but I think I'll let this idle for a bit.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Illcomebacktothislater.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>I went to a bookstore yesterday</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Iwenttoabookstoreyesterd.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Have you ever been to a bookstore? I have, and they are wonderful.</p>
<p>I needed to run some errands yesterday and happened to drive by <a href="https://www.schulerbooks.com/">Schuler Books</a>, an independent store based in Michigan and one I've been going to for decades.</p>
<p>It's been a couple of years since I've been inside a bookstore and oh my goodness what a feeling. Am I the only one that feels a certain calming wonder upon entering any bookstore? Maybe not the giant chain stores because they feel a little yucky to me and it takes the fun out of it, but the local(ish) stores that have been in the neighborhood forever. Mmmm.</p>
<p>Shopping for books by walking around amongst the shelves is an immeasurably better experience than endlessly clicking on the computer. The only reviews to be had are a few hand-written notes in front of some books. One per book. No aggregated score. No algorithm. No ads.</p>
<p>I bought the <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/termination-shock-9780063028050/9780063028050">new Neal Stephenson book</a> (which is honestly why I was there in the first place). But I also bought <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-ten-thousand-doors-of-january-9780316421997/9780316421973">The Ten Thousand Doors of January</a> and a <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-selected-poetry-of-rainer-maria-rilke-bilingual-edition/9780679722014">book of poetry by Rilke</a>. During checkout, they said that they loved the Rilke book and how it included the original German-language versions. They then inserted a bookmark in each book, and packed them all into a crisp paper bag and said, "Enjoy!"</p>

<p>Bookstores are the best.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/19/Iwenttoabookstoreyesterd.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>About that M10 Monochrom</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/AboutthatM10Monochrom.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I've been thinking a lot lately about getting a Leica M10 Monochrom. I know, I know, it's a bad idea. I had the Leica Q2 Monochrom and sold it. But but but! The idea is that if I consider myself a primarily black and white photographer, and I do, there's nothing better than the M10M. Except it's way too expensive for something so limited. Then I had a genius idea. What about an M10-P again? But, and here's the genius part, set up Lightroom to convert raw images to black and white on import! That way I never have to actually see each image in color and decide if I should convert it to black and white. It's darn close to shooting B&W right in the camera. Later, if I do happen to get curious, I can peek at the original color version, just in case. Ha? Ya?</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/AboutthatM10Monochrom.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>No news is good news</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Nonewsisgoodnews.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I have been avoiding news sites, mostly successfully, for a while now. Life is better without knowing about things I neither care nor can do anything about. The Economist once a week is enough. When I do accidentally dip into NYT or similar, I am reminded that the Bad Guys really are winning and it depresses me to no end.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Nonewsisgoodnews.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Social features</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Socialfeatures.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Adding social or collaborative features to an app invariably makes that app worse. (Unless of course that's what the app is <i>for</i>)</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/Socialfeatures.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>Three years at the Lathe</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/ThreeyearsattheLathe.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>I've been writing in my wiki at <a href="https://rudimentarylathe.wiki">rudimentarylathe.wiki</a> for over three years. It now contains 2766 "tiddlers". That's the longest I've stuck with any platform in as long as I can remember. I often think about moving to something newer or prettier or whatever, but in short order I'm back in TiddlyWiki. It's comfortable.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/18/ThreeyearsattheLathe.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>I don't worry too much about "Lock-In"</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/14/IdontworrytoomuchaboutLo.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://youneedastereo.com/#Ton%20Zijlstra%20is%20careful%20about%20using%20notetaking%20app%20features">Phil asks</a>:</p>
		<blockquote>In short, are the short-term gains from using whatever fancy, proprietary features in a tool worth the cost of spending time worrying about lock-in, and the lost time or lost search results when you can't query all of your notes at once? </blockquote>
<p>Again, I think this comes down to how and when the notes are most useful. For things like my Daybook, I'm convinced that simple text files (<a href="https://orgmode.org/">Org mode</a>, in my case) are best. They're mostly for searching later. Sometimes <i>much</i> later. No other features are necessary to get value from my notes.</p>
<p>But for, say, notes about an active project, features such as transclusion and backlinking and spatial presentation can be very useful and totally worth the trade-off of (maybe) being "broken" some day in the future. I have notes from many defunct apps that can still search in a pinch. Voodoopad, Circus Ponies, etc. I just made sure to export them as best I could when it became obvious the software was going away. Spotlight almost always finds what I was looking for. It's not ideal, but it's not a big problem, either. Sure, I lost the fancy bits in translation, but I no longer need those features for those notes. As long as the fancy stuff is just layered over extractable plain text, it's probably never going to be an issue. Stop wasting time hand-wringing and get on with it, I say 😁.</p>
<p>What about my "Second Brain" or "Digital Garden" or "Zettelkastan" or whatever the Productivity Bloggers are labeling their random pile of notes these days? This falls somewhere between needing to be useful now and remaining useful forever, so it muddies things a little. I'm convinced that if one is trying to (lord help me) "synthesize knowledge" from their notes, the extra organization or presentation features are in every way superior <b>today</b> to a wall of plain text notes. Why not take advantage of it all?</p>
<p>(Of course, I use plain text Org files for nearly all my personal notes, but that's not because I fear lock-in. It's because I love Org mode so much.)</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/14/IdontworrytoomuchaboutLo.html</guid>
</item><item>
<title>This has no title</title>
<link>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/17/Thishasnotitle.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>And what if it worked the same way? For example, this post has no title. I <a href="  https://rudimentarylathe.wiki/#Tinderbox%20Drummer%20blog">wrote up some notes</a>.</p>
    ]]></description>
<guid>https://notes.baty.net/posts/2021/11/17/Thishasnotitle.html</guid>
</item>
</channel>

</rss>